Finding Aid for the Aron Kuppermann Papers 1946-2012
Caltech Archives
- Research Files, Series 7.
  - Technical Files, Subseries 2.
    - Boundry conditions, November 1987 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Behavior of body fixed surface functions (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Wigner rotation matrices as a representation of the 3-D rotation group, December 1987 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Scattering theory with local hyperspherical surface functions, October 1988 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Independent 5-D reference functions, December 1989 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - General treatment of geometric phase effect I, March 1991-March 1996 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - General treatment of geometric phase effect II, March 1991-March 1996 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - General treatment of geometric phase effect III, March 1991-March 1996 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - A new look at symmetric hyperspherical coordinates I, August 1991-February 1992 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - A new look at symmetric hyperspherical coordinates II, August 1991-February 1992 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - A new look at symmetric hyperspherical coordinates III, August 1991-February 1992 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Comparison of different principal axis of inertia hyperspherical coordinate systems I, September 1991 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Comparison of different principal axis of inertia hyperspherical coordinate systems II, September 1991 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Comparison of different principal axis of inertia hyperspherical coordinate systems III, September 1991 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Comparison of forward and reverse exact transition state transmission coefficients, January 1992 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Geometrical properties of the maps of 4-particle systems, March-May 1992 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Commutation between coordinate transformations and function operators, May 1992 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Construction of row-orthogonal matrices of dimensions 3 times N, May-June 1992 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - N-particle Hamiltonian in principal moment of inertia frame I, May-August 1992 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - N-particle Hamiltonian in principal moment of inertia frame II, May-August 1992 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - General considerations about the N-particle Hamiltonian in principal moment of inertia hyperspherical coordinates I, August 1992-November 1995 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - General considerations about the N-particle Hamiltonian in principal moment of inertia hyperspherical coordinates II, August 1992-November 1995 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - General considerations about the N-particle Hamiltonian in principal moment of inertia hyperspherical coordinates III, August 1992-November 1995 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - General considerations about the N-particle Hamiltonian in principal moment of inertia hyperspherical coordinates IV, August 1992-November 1995 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - General considerations about the N-particle Hamiltonian in principal moment of inertia hyperspherical coordinates V, August 1992-November 1995 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Transformations of coordinates in Jacobi matter form, October 1992 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - The Born-Oppenheimer expansion in mass scaled Jacobi coordinates, December 1992-September 1995 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Relation between adiabatic and diabatic representations, January 1993 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Symmetry analysis of collinear triatomic reactive scattering, February 1993 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Symmetry decomposition for collinear triatomic reactions, February 1993 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Consideration about 2MD and 5MD basis functions and their symmetries, March-April 1993 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Estimate of the effect of narrow resonances on collinear rate constants, May 1993 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Diabatization procedure for the first two electronic state of H3, September 1993-January 1994 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - One dimensional basis sets, November 1993 (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Rederivation of some formulas of Bowman chapter, December 1993 (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Some thoughts on the calculation of the gain for the concurrent use of two computers linked by a network, January 1994 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - The shapes of intersecting potential energy, April 1994 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Bohm's mechanics applied to molecular systems, April 1994 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Diabatization procedure, May 1994-October 1995 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - A new switching function, January 1995 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Analysis of the poles of triatomic systems in row orthonormal coordinates, February 1995 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Pack's rotationary quasi adiabatic expansion, February 1995 (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Timedelay analysis of multichannel scattering problems, February-April 1995 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Decomposition of the multichannel scattering amplitude into hard-sphere potential and resonant parts, March-April 1995 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Relation between Yarkoni and hyperspherical coordinates and matrix elements, June 1995 (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Relation between space fixed and body fixed gradients for N-particle systems, September 1995 (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - The adiabatic to diabatic transformation for conical intersections angle, September 1995-September 1996 (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Considerations about external and internal angular momenta, October 1995 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Single valuedness and boundary conditions issues, January-April 1996 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Angular momentum operators, March 1996 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - The 3-body hamiltonian, April-July 1996 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Relation between principal axes of inertia and Jacobi body fixed hyperspherical coordinate operators, May 1996 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - The 3 and 4-body Hamiltonian, May 1996 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - The 4-body Hamiltonian, September 1996 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - The chain rule in matrix form, October 1996-February 1997 (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Singular value decomposition, October 1996 (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Thoughts about matrix form of gradient operator, October 1996 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Hyperspherical coordinates for H3, November 1996 (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Partial wave expansion in row-orthonormal hyperspherical coordinates for 3 and 4 body systems, December 1996 (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Single valuedness and continuity for nuclear wave functions of triatomic and tetraatomic systems, January 1997 (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Transformations issues, January-August 1997 (Box 93, Folder 13)
    - A possible change of the row orthonormal hyperspherical coordinates, March 1997 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Reactive scattering with row orthonormal hyperspherical coordinates I, March 1997 (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Reactive scattering with row orthonormal hyperspherical coordinates II, March 1997 (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Orthogonality of the Jacobi coordinate transformation, July 1997 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Boundary conditions in the decomposition of a vector field into longitudial and transverse components, October 1997 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Symmetry properties of diabatic wave functions, November-December 1997 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - H3 coupling tables, November 1997-February 1998 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Coupling calculations, February 1998 (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Mixing classical and quantum mechanics, May 1998 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Individual particle properties and statistical ensemble averages in classical and quantum mechanics, July 1998 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Hyperspherical harmonics for tetraatomic systems, January-July 2000 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Considerations about generalized angular momentum operator, March 2000 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - The Hamiltonian for N-body systems in row-orthogonormal hyperspherical coordinates, April 2000 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Hamiltonian for N-body systems in row-orthonormal hyperspherical coordinates, May-July 2000 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Body fixed and space fixed angular momentum operators, May 2000 (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Parity properties of the ROHC harmonics, March 2001 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Geometric phase effect in tetraatomics, May 2001 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Comparison of effects of pseudo rotations and inversions on triatomic and tetraatomic systems, July 2001 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Hyperspherical harmonics in weak interaction region for tetraatomic systems, October 2001-February 2004 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Triatomic and tetraatomic hyperspherical harmonics including the geometric phase effect I, July 2002 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Triatomic and tetraatomic hyperspherical harmonics including the geometric phase effect II, July 2002 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Triatomic and tetraatomic hyperspherical harmonics including the geometric phase effect III, July 2002 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Triatomic and tetraatomic hyperspherical harmonics including the geometric phase effect IV, July 2002 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Triatomic and tetraatomic hyperspherical harmonics including the geometric phase effect V, July 2002 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Triatomic and tetraatomic hyperspherical harmonics including the geometric phase effect VI, July 2002 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Triatomic and tetraatomic hyperspherical harmonics including the geometric phase effect VII, July 2002 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Coordinations about angular momentum operations, January 2003 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - The Hamiltonian in ROHC, July 2003 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - The hyperadius dependence of surface functions in the asymptotic region, March 2004 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Hyperspherical harmonics in weak interaction region for tetraatomic systems, October 2004 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - A new look at hyperspherical harmonics for triatomic systems with and without the geometric phase, December 2004 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - An improved reference potential for the atom triatom weak interaction region, March 2005 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Analysis of tetraatomic systems, September 2005 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Considerations about a backword integrator to generate physical wave functions, November 2006 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - The angular momentum commutation relations in 3D and 4D spaces, August-December 2007 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - An alternate set of angular momentum operators for 3 and 4 body systems, March-April 2008 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Relation between Mukhtarova and Efros and Wang and Kuppermann triatomic hyperspherical harmonics, March-May 2008 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Considerations about changes of variables in the evaluations of scalar product, February 2009 (Box 98, Folder 9)
- Computing, Series 8.
  - San Diego Supercomputer Center (SDSC), Subseries 1.
    - San Diego Supercomputing Center Committees
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meetings, 1985 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meetings, 1986-1988 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, March 1991 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, June 1991 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, March 1992 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, December 1992 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, March 1993 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, September 1993 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, March 1994 (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, September 1994 (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, March 1995 (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, June 1995 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, September 1995 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, December 1995 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, March 1996 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - SDSC Steeing Committee meeting, June 1996 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - SDSC Allocation Committee meetings, 1985-1991 (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - SDSC Allocation Committee meetings, 1992-1993 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - San Diego Supercomputing Center Proposals
    - "Caltech Concurrent Computation Program: use of the Cray-2 for scientific Computation", 1987-1988 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - "Ab initio calculation of reaction cross sections", 1987-1988 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - "Ab initio calculation of reaction cross sections", 1989-1991 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - "Ab initio calculation of reaction cross sections on parallel supercomputers", 1992-1993 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - "SDSC Consortium parallel computing proposal, 1992-1993 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - "Ab initio calculation of reaction cross sections and quantum mechanical streamlines for atom-diatom reactions", 1994-1995 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - National Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure (NPACI) proposals, 1998-2001 (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - National Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure (NPACI) proposals, 2002-2005 (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - "Quantum state to state reaction dynamics", 2006-2008 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - "Quantum state to state reaction dynamics", 2009-2011 (Box 101, Folder 10)
    - San Diego Supercomputing Center miscellany
    - Time allocationon SDSC Cray, 1986-1987 (Box 101, Folder 11)
    - Time allocationon SDSC Cray, 1988-1989 (Box 101, Folder 12)
    - Time allocationon SDSC Cray, 1990-1997 (Box 101, Folder 13)
    - SDSC correspondence, 1985-1997 (Box 101, Folder 14)
  - Intel Delta Parallel Supercomputer, Subseries 2.
    - Concurrent Supercomputing Consortium (CSC), Group on Parallel Supercomputing Applications Consortium at Caltech (PSACC), 1990-1993 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - News clippings related to the Concurrent Supercomputing Consortium's acquisition of the Intel Touchstone Delta System, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Allocation policy for Intel Delta System, 1990-1991 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Intel Delta dedication, May 31, 1991 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Delta Parallel Supercomputer Policy Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Intel Delta user group meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Intel Delta\Gamma applications, 1991-1994 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Intel Delta\Gamma time allocation, 1991-1994 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Intel Delta\Gamma allocation usage, 1991-1994 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Proposal: "Calculation of reaction cross sections and rateconstants on the Caltech Delta parallel supercomputer", 1991-1993 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Proposal: "Institute for High-Performance Computing (IHPC)", 1993 (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - Caltech Concurrent Computation Program (CCCP), Subseries 3.
    - CCCP financial matters, 1985-1986 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - CCCP reports, 1985-1986 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - CCCP reports, 1987-1988 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - CCCP review: "Quantum chemical reaction dynamics with concurrent processors", 1988 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - CCCP research funds, 1990-1992 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding the Center for Research on Parallel Computation (CRPC), 1990-1994 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding the Center for Advanced Computing Research (CACR), 1994-1996 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Caltech Computational Research, selected projects, 1995 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - JPL\Caltech Supercomputing Project, Subseries 4.
    - Cray X\MP Project, 1992 (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - Cray X\MP Project, 1993-1994 (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - Cray X\MP Project, 1995 (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - Cray X\MP Project, 1996-1998 (Box 103, Folder 12)
    - JPL Cray computer time allocation, 1998-1999 (Box 103, Folder 13)
    - JPL Cray computer time allocation, 2000-2001 (Box 103, Folder 14)
    - CASA Gigabit Network
    - CASA Network plan, 1990 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Report: "CASA Gigabit Network Testbed: Quantum chemical reaction dynamics", 1991 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - CASA applications workshop, 1992 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - CASA correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - CASA correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 104, Folder 5)
- Biographical and Personal Material, Series 9.
  - Biographical sketch (several versions), 1955, 1980, 1984, 1989, 1991, 1993, 1998, 2006 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1959-1960 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1962, 1968, 1976, 1978, 1980, 1984, 1992, 2002 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Faculty profile statements, 1963, 1970, 1991-2006 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - List of publications, 1984, 1993, 2010-2011 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - List of publications on theoretical topics, 1989, 1993 (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - "Ten most significant experimental contributions of Aron Kuppermann: 1960 through 1977", 1978 (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - "Ten most significant theoretical contributions of Aron Kuppermann: 1963 through 1977", 1978 (Box 104, Folder 13)
  - "Ten most significant experimental and theoretical contributions of Aron Kuppermann: 1963 through 1977", 1978 (Box 104, Folder 14)
  - "An account of Aron kuppermann's scientific contributions from September 1955 through December 1978", 1979 (Box 104, Folder 15)
  - "Aron Kuppermann's most important scientific contributions", 1982 (Box 104, Folder 16)
  - "An account of Aron kuppermann's contributions to theoretical chemistry", 1989 (Box 104, Folder 17)
  - Consulting files
  - Varian Associates, 1965-1967 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - TRW Systems Corporation, 1971-1976 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Jet Propulsion Laboratory, 1979 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - International Advisory Panel, Chinese University Development Project, 1983-1986, 1991 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Education and early science
  - University of Sao Paulo: Mathematical physics, 1952 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - University of Edinburgh: Exercises in quantum theory, 1953 January-March (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - University of Edinburgh: Nuclear physics, January-March 1953 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - University of Edinburgh: Quantum mechanics, January-March 1953 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - University of Edinburgh: Electronics, April 1953 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Atomic Energy Research Establishment (AERE), England: Isotope School, July-August 1953 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    Course on handling and using radioactive isotopes.
  - Seminar on Bohm's paper, 1953 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    Includes correspondence with Albert Einstein, Enrico Fermi, W. Heisenberg, Wolfgang Pauli, Leonard Isaac Schiff, and Inge-Ernst Sommerfeld.
  - University of Notre Dame: Quantum theory, 1953-1954 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - University of Notre Dame: Chemistry notebook, 1953-1954 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - University of Notre Dame: Electrodynamics, 1953-1954 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - University of Notre Dame: Problems in physical chemistry, 1953-1954 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - University of Notre Dame: Ph.D. dissertation, August 1955 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    Title of dissertation: "Decomposition of n-Butane in an electric discharge."
  - Instituto de Energia Atomica, Brazil: Radiation Chemistry, 1959-1960 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - University of Illinois: Physics 482, 1963 (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Caltech: Physics 205, 1972-1973 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    Class taught by Richard Feynman.
  - Biographical listings
  - American Chemical Society Directory of Graduate Research, 1961, 1965-2001 (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - American Men and Women in Science, 1972, 1975, 1978, 1981, 1991, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - American Men of Science, 1965 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - Dictionary of International Biography, 1970 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Men of Achievement, 1970 (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - National Register of prominent Americans, 1973 (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - The Blue Book (publication), 1969 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Who's Who in America, 1966-1967, 1969, 1971, 2003 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Who's Who in American Education, 1969 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Who's Who in Atoms, 1962, 1964 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Who's Who in Frontiers of Science and Technology, 1985 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Who's Who in Technology Today, 1982 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Who's Who in the West, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Who's Who in the World Jewry, 1969 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - World Who's Who in Science, 1967 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Awards and Honors
  - The National Chemistry Honor Society, Phi Lambda Upsilon, 1956 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - Richard M. Badger Teaching Prize, Caltech, 1996 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Sigma Xi honorary membership, 1997 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Royal Society of Chemistry Award: S.F. Boys- A Rahman Lectureship, 1998-1999 (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Caltech Graduate Student Council Excellence in Teaching Award, 1999 (Box 107, Folder 14)
  - News clippings, articles and interviews
  - Caltech News, December 1975 (Box 107, Folder 15)
    Vol. 9, no. 9.
  - Ambassador College report, May 29, 1905 (Box 107, Folder 16)
  - Los Angeles Times, May 13, 1979 (Box 107, Folder 17)
  - Pasadena Star News, November 13, 1990 (Box 107, Folder 18)
  - Engineering & Science, 1996 (Box 107, Folder 19)
  - Caltech Oral History project, 2001 (Box 107, Folder 20)
  - Personal, Miscellany
  - Correspondence regarding joining Caltech, 1962-1964 (Box 107, Folder 21)
  - Leave of absence, 1968-1969 (Box 107, Folder 22)
  - Leave of absence, 1976-1977 (Box 107, Folder 23)
  - Leave of absence, 1984 (Box 107, Folder 24)
  - Leave of absence, 1992 (Box 107, Folder 25)
  - Leave of absence, 1998 (Box 107, Folder 26)
  - Portrait photos, 1979, 1997 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Copy of Kuppermann's birth certificate (in Portuguese), 1959 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Kuppermann's 75th birthday celebration, Caltech, March 30-31, 2001 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Kuppermann's obituaries, 2011 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Kuppermann's Memorial Symposium, Caltech, October 23, 2012 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Caltech, Miscellany
  - List of past graduate students, 1968, 1983, 1985, 2012 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Research group social activities, 1987, 11989, 1999 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Research group contact information list, 1991-1992, 1996 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Research group calendar, November 1998- March 2000 (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - Office procedures, 2003 (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Kuppermann's blank letterheads, undated (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Kuppermann's Web page printouts, 2010 (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - Appointment books, 1991-1994 (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - Appointment books, 1995-1998 (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Appointment books, 1999-2001 (Box 108, Folder 15)
  - Appointment books, 2002-2004, 2006 (Box 108, Folder 16)